<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-08-27T12:21:01-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Vera Breen - Author</title><subtitle>Artificial Intelligence trends and concepts made easy.</subtitle><author><name>Vera Breen</name></author><entry><title type="html">AI Art and Authorship</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/AI-art.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI Art and Authorship" /><published>2023-08-27T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-08-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/AI-art</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/AI-art.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="killing-careers">Killing Careers?</h2>

<p>Let’s look at Sally, a 30 year old artist who creates commissioned character art and book covers for fantasy novelists. As we discuss the ethics around AI art, we’ll keep Sally in mind.</p>

<p>Discussions between authors and Sally have pointed to one opinion - using AI kills careers and snatches creator content without consent. Let’s look at the workflow of AI to talk about why -</p>
<ol>
  <li>Tools like Dall-E scrape the internet and take a peek at Sally’s art.</li>
  <li>Dall-E says “Sure, I can use that style to generate my own versions.”</li>
  <li>Authors publish AI art for sales. This might include printables for books and social media posts.</li>
</ol>

<p>Sally hates this for several reasons. First, AI puts her out of a job. With AI on the loose, her commissioned art can be replaced by Dall-E’s almost-free generated art. For Sally, AI art is a death sentence. She’s built a niche and following around an industry that’s being replaced with automation.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>For artists, AI is a death sentence</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Another detractor – AI is trained by looking at Sally’s work. Sally went to art school and sweated for years to develop a unique art style. In seconds, Dall-E learned and replicated her content. Remember, everything AI does is derivative. AI models are trained by looking at people’s work and making iterations based on prompts. <strong>Dall-E isn’t advancing art in the same way Sally can. Dall-E doesn’t need a paycheck to eat.</strong></p>

<h2 id="authors-are-broke">Authors Are Broke</h2>

<p>Authors are frustrated too. For indie novelists, AI can create character art and covers that were previously unattainable due to financial constraints. Not all authors can afford to pay Sally. AI tools like Dall-E and Artbreeder open the door to integrated art when you’re broke as a joke.</p>

<p>The author and art communities has unanimously agreed that AI art is harmful, but we’ve still seen hundreds of popular art and author accounts post AI generated work. Use at your own risk and be aware that authors with significant traction have been cancelled for AI art.</p>

<h2 id="using-public-domain">Using Public Domain</h2>

<p>“But Vera, I’m really broke.”</p>

<p>There are options.</p>

<p>First and foremost, pay artists when you <em>can</em>. As novelists, we’re excited to be paid! Treat artists the same way you want novelists to be treated.</p>

<p>Get inspired by work in the public domain. Sites like <a href="www.pexels.com">www.pexels.com</a> are a great source for royalty-free art. Take a look at their <a href="https://www.pexels.com/license/">license page</a> for information on how you can use their content.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.nga.gov/open-access-images.html">Open Access</a> images are a wonderful tool. Read through their <a href="https://www.nga.gov/notices/open-access-policy.html">license policy</a> as well.</p>

<p>A hard-mode option is to train as an artist. Many are afraid that their work isn’t good enough, but readers appreciate seeing their favorite characters come to life, even if the art is rough.</p>

<p>Finally, pay for stock images. I got really inspired by <a href="https://www.stocksy.com/IbaiAcevedoo/showcase?page=1">Ibai Acevedoo’s</a> work, and liked that I could pay $15 for photography with a pretty generous standard royalty free license.</p>

<h2 id="disagree-start-a-discussion-on-my-instagram">Disagree? Start a discussion on my Instagram</h2>

<p>https://www.instagram.com/verabreenauthor/</p>]]></content><author><name>Vera Breen</name></author><category term="opinion" /><category term="AI" /><category term="ethics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI art makes character art fast. Is it ethical?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Author Websites with Github Pages</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/author-website-gh-pages.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Author Websites with Github Pages" /><published>2023-08-24T15:14:20-06:00</published><updated>2023-08-24T15:14:20-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/author-website-gh-pages</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/author-website-gh-pages.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="why">Why?</h2>

<p>Do you like this website? It was free! In this guide, I’ll drag you a high-level process for building THIS VERY WEBSITE (wow!) with GitHub Pages. If you don’t have prior coding knowledge, this article might not be enough.</p>

<p>GitHub has great articles on how to complete this process, but I want to document the gotchas I experienced while setting up this bomb-ass site.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>P.S. GitHub can do other cool things for authors too. <a href="https://www.gitkraken.com/gitkon/git-for-writers">Here’s one author’s experience with git</a>.</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="nice-to-haves">Nice-To-Haves</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Prior coding knowledge or the time to learn</li>
  <li>Command line knowledge</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="1-github">1. Github</h2>

<p>Match your author name to your <a href="www.github.com">GitHub</a> account username. I (Vera Breen) might pick <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">verabreen</code> as my GitHub account name.</p>

<p>If you’re new to git, consider using a tool like <a href="https://www.gitkraken.com/">Git Kraken</a> to organize your project.</p>

<h3 id="make-the-project">Make the Project</h3>

<p>Pick where your code will live. Each website will live in it’s own project (works like a computer folder). To create a new project, follow <a href="https://docs.github.com/en/pages/quickstart#creating-your-website">this guide</a>.</p>

<p>Complete “Creating Your Website”, skip the last section “Change Title and Description.” We’ll deal with the title later.</p>

<p>SO IMPORTANT!! This sets your default website URL, so use your author name! For me, that might be -</p>
<ul>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">verabreen.github.io</code></li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">authorverabreen.github.io</code></li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">vmbreen.github.io</code></li>
</ul>

<p>GitHub will give you these domain names for free, as long as they end in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">github.io</code>.</p>

<p>Your live website will live at <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">www.yourname.github.io</code>. It won’t work quite yet, though.</p>

<p>This is where I might have lied to you. To get the <em>optional</em> cute URL <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">www.yourname.com</code>, have to pay a yearly domain fee (usually $12) for the name. I buy mine from Google Domains. <a href="https://docs.github.com/en/pages/configuring-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site/managing-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site">Setting up custom domain names can be found here</a></p>

<h3 id="install-tools">Install Tools</h3>

<p>Install the following tools to create your website -</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Jekyll</strong> builds your website! <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/">Here are the instructions.</a></li>
  <li><strong>Visual Studio Code</strong>. You may use Scrivener, Word, or Google Docs to write your novels. Visual Studio Code (VS Code) is a similar tool for developers. If it looks scary, remember it’s just a fancy Microsoft Word. Download and install that <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/download">Here is the download.</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="bring-the-project-to-your-computer">Bring the Project to Your Computer</h3>

<p>Let’s bring the project to your computer.</p>

<p>The workflow will be -</p>
<ul>
  <li>Write content on your computer and test it</li>
  <li>Send it to GitHub</li>
  <li>Launch the website</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>If this is brand new, find a coder friend and have them work alongside you.</p>
</blockquote>

<h4 id="git-clone">Git Clone</h4>

<p>Use your terminal to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">git clone</code> your repository. This brings the code to your computer to work on (like downloading an email attachment to open on your computer). <a href="https://youtu.be/8JJ101D3knE?si=kK52Btu97jP030ZT">Here</a> is a great video on using git.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8JJ101D3knE?si=gaChcmFbR_ee-c9u" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<h4 id="changes-in-vs-code">Changes in VS Code</h4>

<p>Open the entire folder in VS Code. Consider downloading a Jekyll project plugin! You will be making changes in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">posts/</code> folder (we’ll learn how later).</p>

<h4 id="jekyll-serve">Jekyll Serve</h4>

<p>Before making changes, test your installation with Jekyll. I chose to add the starter site first. Inside of your project folder, follow the instructions <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/">here</a>.</p>

<p>Some tips -</p>
<ul>
  <li>Reload the webpage (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">localhost:4000</code>) after you make changes</li>
  <li>If your changes aren’t showing, restart the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll serve</code> command</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="git-commit--push">Git Commit + Push</h4>

<p>Use git commands to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">git add</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">git commit</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">git push</code>. <em>Your website won’t launch until you do this</em>. Go to the URL you chose above, such as www.yourprojectname.github.io, and double-check that your website is present.</p>

<h4 id="optional-pick-branch-strategy">Optional: Pick Branch Strategy</h4>

<p>Some authors want to make a “work in progress” branch where they can save undeployed changes. This allows authors to commit and push changes without them going live on the website.</p>

<p>I live by the YOLO principle and make changes directly on <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">main</code> because I am fastidious about checking my changes on my computer first.</p>

<h2 id="creating-content">Creating Content</h2>

<p>Now you want to add things to your website. By default, you can add markdown pages in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> folder, git commit them, and have your website. Figure out how to add a post now. Some tips -</p>
<ul>
  <li>Copy and paste an existing post page. There should be one called “_posts/2023-08-26-welcome-to-jekyll.markdown”.</li>
  <li>The post above tells you exactly what needs to go in a post.</li>
  <li>Play around with markdown files. <a href="https://docs.github.com/en/get-started/writing-on-github/getting-started-with-writing-and-formatting-on-github/basic-writing-and-formatting-syntax">You can add links, images, and formatting</a>.</li>
</ul>

<p>The banner pictures live in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">assets/img/posts</code> in a folder with the date. Make sure your resolution is high enough (over 1500 pixels).</p>

<p>After this, the themeing is purely aesthetic.</p>

<h3 id="picking-themes">Picking Themes</h3>

<p><a href="https://www.bestjekyllthemes.com/theme/the-mvm-the-mvm.github.io/">I used this one</a>. There are excellent instructions in his README to install.</p>

<p><strong>I wanted to make HTML and CSS changes</strong>, so I went the route of downloading the project manually and copy-pasting into my project folder. To do this -</p>
<ul>
  <li>Erase everything that already exists in the folder except your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.git</code> files.</li>
  <li>Paste. Make sure to exclude their <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.git</code> files.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Tip! Some folders (like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_site/</code>) are built every time you restart the server. Make sure to make changes in the top-level <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">assets/</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_layout</code>, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_include</code> folders if you’re getting wild with code changes.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="deployment-and-beyond">Deployment and Beyond</h2>

<p>Making changes to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_config.yml</code> is the last step to build your Jekyll project. For the theme above, I had to -</p>
<ul>
  <li>Change the site settings at the top of the file</li>
  <li>Adjust the author settings</li>
  <li>Adjust the social media settings. These get tagged in every author element (an example is the author page and post pages toward the bottom)</li>
</ul>

<p>If you need help, we can set up a one-on-one consult session, or you can check the newsletter for upcoming group classes.</p>

<p>Enjoy!</p>]]></content><author><name>Vera Breen</name></author><category term="websites" /><category term="github" /><category term="DIY" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Custom author websites can rock branding... but how to you set one up for free?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pleasure and Picking Titles</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/picking-titles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pleasure and Picking Titles" /><published>2023-08-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-08-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/picking-titles</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/picking-titles.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="cover-and-titles">Cover and Titles</h2>

<p>I stumbled across <a href="https://www.thecreativepenn.com/2018/10/08/doubling-down-on-what-you-love-and-opportunities-when-publishing-wide-my-ninc-2018-round-up/">this creative penn article</a> when researching how and what to title my book. I’m scared! I have two shots to capture readership.</p>
<ol>
  <li>Have a bomb.com title</li>
  <li>Pick a great cover</li>
</ol>

<p>I chose my cover art, but as you can see, <em>mmmm has sex with ff in a basement</em> is a lacking title.</p>

<center><img src="./assets/img/posts/20230801/ebookcover.png" width="540" /></center>
<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="titling-for-the-id">Titling for the Id</h2>

<p>The article above states that titling for the id – the things that scream “pleasure” – communicates to the reader that the book will contain something juicy that they’ll love.</p>

<p>Here’s the list of pleasures contained in my novel -</p>
<ul>
  <li>Reverse harems (<em>sigh</em>, I’ll never get over them) and found family</li>
  <li>Every mm and ff spicy combination with my 4 male and 2 female protagonists</li>
  <li>mlm and wlw</li>
  <li>Fucking your best friend</li>
  <li>Dangerous men with tattoos</li>
  <li>Twisted power dynamics</li>
  <li>A twinkle of exhibitionism and BDSM</li>
  <li>Scandalous ballgowns</li>
</ul>

<p>I briefly considered throwing my latin-inspired setting name (Domus Aeterna) into the title, but was quickly scolded. It’s not readable and it doesn’t convey that are there 6 people fucking each other and finding love in a dangerous temple.</p>

<h2 id="titles-in-my-genre">Titles in my Genre</h2>

<p>My omg-so-amazing mentor <a href="http://www.jeannielin.com/">Jeannie Lin</a> told me to go list some book titles in my genre. See what’s selling!</p>

<p><em>Queen Takes Knights</em> by Joely Sue Burkhart. I think this is the winner of “reverse harem titles with bomb covers.” I snatched these books up in an instant and knew exactly what I was getting into. The title definitely embodies the concept of powerful women (queen), sex (takes), and that reverse harem (knights, plural). Also, let’s take a moment to gush over that cover art. I love the chess reference (intrigue).</p>

<iframe type="text/html" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups" width="336" height="550" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" style="max-width:100%" src="https://read.amazon.com/kp/card?asin=B076JFJ8ZF&amp;preview=inline&amp;linkCode=kpe&amp;ref_=cm_sw_r_kb_dp_BXAAJ01797XPC12812GM"></iframe>

<p><em>Sex Wizards</em> by Alethea Faust. Love this! The series title doesn’t fuck around. It gets straight to the point.</p>

<iframe type="text/html" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups" width="336" height="550" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" style="max-width:100%" src="https://read.amazon.com/kp/card?asin=B09J98KB99&amp;preview=inline&amp;linkCode=kpe&amp;ref_=cm_sw_r_kb_dp_Z8623A6N8334SYZ2X5VB"></iframe>

<p><em>Helfyre</em> by Mariel Pomeroy. Hel- (There will be dangerous demons within), -fyre (Burning tension? Romance? I love it all)</p>

<iframe type="text/html" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups" width="336" height="550" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" style="max-width:100%" src="https://read.amazon.com/kp/card?asin=B09QT71SFD&amp;preview=inline&amp;linkCode=kpe&amp;ref_=cm_sw_r_kb_dp_MRVM7RKZ951RXR6YRXS1"></iframe>

<p>While doing this exercise, I also noticed reverse harem books in by TBR that I had to dig for. Without clear titles, they got chucked onto the “rh” shelf with a guess in Goodreads.</p>]]></content><author><name>Vera Breen</name></author><category term="titles" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Walking through my title-picking process.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kindle Unlimited Vs Vella</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Kindle-Vs-Vella.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kindle Unlimited Vs Vella" /><published>2023-03-18T15:14:20-06:00</published><updated>2023-03-18T15:14:20-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Kindle-Vs-Vella</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Kindle-Vs-Vella.html"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name>Vera Breen</name></author><category term="kindle" /><category term="vella" /><category term="publishing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Below Domus Aetera</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/bda.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Below Domus Aetera" /><published>2021-08-27T13:32:20-06:00</published><updated>2021-08-27T13:32:20-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/bda</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/bda.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="preorder">Preorder!</h2>

<p><a href="https://a.co/d/9k7aB0m">Preorder - Dec 1, 2023</a>.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Reverse harems, and found family</li>
  <li>Every mmmm and ff spicy combination</li>
  <li>Polyamorous mlm and wlw</li>
  <li>Fucking your best friend</li>
  <li>Dangerous men with tattoos</li>
  <li>Twisted power dynamics</li>
  <li>A twinkle of exhibitionism and BDSM</li>
  <li>Scandalous ballgowns</li>
</ul>

<p><a data-pin-do="embedBoard" data-pin-board-width="800" data-pin-scale-height="640" data-pin-scale-width="120" href="https://www.pinterest.com/verabreenauthor/cesa-and-yassina/"></a></p>]]></content><author><name>Vera Breen</name></author><category term="book releases" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Book notes for BDA]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Save the Cat</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/save-the-cat.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Save the Cat" /><published>2021-03-24T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-03-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/save-the-cat</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/save-the-cat.html"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name>Armando Maynez</name></author><category term="plotting" /><category term="save the cat" /><category term="scrivener" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How did I use Scrivener and Save the Cat?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Erotica - GitHub vs GitGud</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/GitHub-vs-GitGub.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Erotica - GitHub vs GitGud" /><published>2021-03-12T12:32:20-07:00</published><updated>2021-03-12T12:32:20-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/GitHub-vs-GitGub</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/GitHub-vs-GitGub.html"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name>Vera Breen</name></author><category term="github" /><category term="git" /><category term="erotica" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using git can be a gamechanger for saving versions, but how does erotica fit in with terms of service?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Horny Jail - Amazon’s Erotica Category</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Horny-Jail.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Horny Jail - Amazon’s Erotica Category" /><published>2021-02-28T11:32:20-07:00</published><updated>2021-02-28T11:32:20-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Horny-Jail</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Horny-Jail.html"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name>Vera Breen</name></author><category term="publishing" /><category term="vella" /><category term="kindle" /><category term="erotica" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Being labeled as "erotica" can tank ad potential. Let's talk about staying out of horny jail.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Marketing Strategy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/marketing-strategy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Marketing Strategy" /><published>2021-01-25T12:32:20-07:00</published><updated>2021-01-25T12:32:20-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/marketing-strategy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/marketing-strategy.html"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name>Vera Briene</name></author><category term="marketing" /><category term="social media" /><category term="websites" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dig into the successes and failures of my marketing strategy]]></summary></entry></feed>