<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-03-31T20:51:15-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Vera Briene - Author</title><subtitle>Artificial Intelligence trends and concepts made easy.</subtitle><author><name>Vera Briene</name></author><entry><title type="html">Beneath Dark Designs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/beneath-dark-designs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beneath Dark Designs" /><published>2024-02-27T12:32:20-07:00</published><updated>2024-02-27T12:32:20-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/beneath-dark-designs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/beneath-dark-designs.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="e-book-and-print-available-in-june">E-book and print available in June</h2>
<h2 id="on-kindle-vella-now"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/kindle-vella/story/B0CN592DMS">On Kindle Vella now!</a></h2>

<p>The temple I serve feeds on rituals of lust and power, but when decay creeps into my world, I’m told to give more - higher stakes, escalating rites, and new partnerships with dangerous men. My offerings stabilize the damage, but now, the temple’s corrupt leader is obsessed with me. How do I escape his twisted control? The four men I’m matched with protect me, but secrets haunt these halls. How do I survive as temple royalty? Who is abusing its power?</p>

<p>Notes -</p>
<ul>
  <li>Why choose?</li>
  <li>Fantasy romance</li>
  <li>Forced proximity</li>
  <li>Magic and mental bonds</li>
  <li>Everyone’s bisexual</li>
  <li>My friend said is was pretty dark, and my other friend asked if I was emotionally ok while writing it</li>
</ul>

<p>Trigger Warnings -</p>
<ul>
  <li>Forced tattoos and branding</li>
  <li>Dubious consent</li>
  <li>Blood and gore</li>
  <li>Murder</li>
  <li>Death</li>
  <li>Self harm, suicide</li>
</ul>

<p>Here’s the vibe -</p>

<p><a data-pin-do="embedBoard" data-pin-board-width="800" data-pin-scale-height="640" data-pin-scale-width="120" href="https://www.pinterest.com/verabrieneauthor/cesa-and-yassina/"></a></p>]]></content><author><name>Vera Briene</name></author><category term="book releases" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Book notes for upcoming fantasy romance]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Author Websites with Github Pages</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/author-website-gh-pages.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Author Websites with Github Pages" /><published>2023-08-24T15:14:20-06:00</published><updated>2023-08-24T15:14:20-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/author-website-gh-pages</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/author-website-gh-pages.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="why">Why?</h2>

<p>Do you like this website? It was free! In this guide, I’ll drag you a high-level process for building THIS VERY WEBSITE (wow!) with GitHub Pages. If you don’t have prior coding knowledge, this article might not be enough.</p>

<p>GitHub has great articles on how to complete this process, but I want to document the gotchas I experienced while setting up this bomb-ass site.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>P.S. GitHub can do other cool things for authors too. <a href="https://www.gitkraken.com/gitkon/git-for-writers">Here’s one author’s experience with git</a>.</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="nice-to-haves">Nice-To-Haves</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Prior coding knowledge or the time to learn</li>
  <li>Command line knowledge</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="1-github">1. Github</h2>

<p>Match your author name to your <a href="www.github.com">GitHub</a> account username. I (Vera Briene) might pick <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">verabriene</code> as my GitHub account name.</p>

<p>If you’re new to git, consider using a tool like <a href="https://www.gitkraken.com/">Git Kraken</a> to organize your project.</p>

<h3 id="make-the-project">Make the Project</h3>

<p>Pick where your code will live. Each website will live in it’s own project (works like a computer folder). To create a new project, follow <a href="https://docs.github.com/en/pages/quickstart#creating-your-website">this guide</a>.</p>

<p>Complete “Creating Your Website”, skip the last section “Change Title and Description.” We’ll deal with the title later.</p>

<p>SO IMPORTANT!! This sets your default website URL, so use your author name! For me, that might be -</p>
<ul>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">verabriene.github.io</code></li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">authorverabriene.github.io</code></li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">vbriene.github.io</code></li>
</ul>

<p>GitHub will give you these domain names for free, as long as they end in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">github.io</code>.</p>

<p>Your live website will live at <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">www.yourname.github.io</code>. It won’t work quite yet, though.</p>

<p>This is where I might have lied to you. To get the <em>optional</em> cute URL <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">www.yourname.com</code>, have to pay a yearly domain fee (usually $12) for the name. I buy mine from Google Domains. <a href="https://docs.github.com/en/pages/configuring-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site/managing-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site">Setting up custom domain names can be found here</a></p>

<h3 id="install-tools">Install Tools</h3>

<p>Install the following tools to create your website -</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Jekyll</strong> builds your website! <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/">Here are the instructions.</a></li>
  <li><strong>Visual Studio Code</strong>. You may use Scrivener, Word, or Google Docs to write your novels. Visual Studio Code (VS Code) is a similar tool for developers. If it looks scary, remember it’s just a fancy Microsoft Word. Download and install that <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/download">Here is the download.</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="bring-the-project-to-your-computer">Bring the Project to Your Computer</h3>

<p>Let’s bring the project to your computer.</p>

<p>The workflow will be -</p>
<ul>
  <li>Write content on your computer and test it</li>
  <li>Send it to GitHub</li>
  <li>Launch the website</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>If this is brand new, find a coder friend and have them work alongside you.</p>
</blockquote>

<h4 id="git-clone">Git Clone</h4>

<p>Use your terminal to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">git clone</code> your repository. This brings the code to your computer to work on (like downloading an email attachment to open on your computer). <a href="https://youtu.be/8JJ101D3knE?si=kK52Btu97jP030ZT">Here</a> is a great video on using git.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8JJ101D3knE?si=gaChcmFbR_ee-c9u" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<h4 id="changes-in-vs-code">Changes in VS Code</h4>

<p>Open the entire folder in VS Code. Consider downloading a Jekyll project plugin! You will be making changes in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">posts/</code> folder (we’ll learn how later).</p>

<h4 id="jekyll-serve">Jekyll Serve</h4>

<p>Before making changes, test your installation with Jekyll. I chose to add the starter site first. Inside of your project folder, follow the instructions <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/">here</a>.</p>

<p>Some tips -</p>
<ul>
  <li>Reload the webpage (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">localhost:4000</code>) after you make changes</li>
  <li>If your changes aren’t showing, restart the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll serve</code> command</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="git-commit--push">Git Commit + Push</h4>

<p>Use git commands to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">git add</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">git commit</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">git push</code>. <em>Your website won’t launch until you do this</em>. Go to the URL you chose above, such as www.yourprojectname.github.io, and double-check that your website is present.</p>

<h4 id="optional-pick-branch-strategy">Optional: Pick Branch Strategy</h4>

<p>Some authors want to make a “work in progress” branch where they can save undeployed changes. This allows authors to commit and push changes without them going live on the website.</p>

<p>I live by the YOLO principle and make changes directly on <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">main</code> because I am fastidious about checking my changes on my computer first.</p>

<h2 id="creating-content">Creating Content</h2>

<p>Now you want to add things to your website. By default, you can add markdown pages in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> folder, git commit them, and have your website. Figure out how to add a post now. Some tips -</p>
<ul>
  <li>Copy and paste an existing post page. There should be one called “_posts/2023-08-26-welcome-to-jekyll.markdown”.</li>
  <li>The post above tells you exactly what needs to go in a post.</li>
  <li>Play around with markdown files. <a href="https://docs.github.com/en/get-started/writing-on-github/getting-started-with-writing-and-formatting-on-github/basic-writing-and-formatting-syntax">You can add links, images, and formatting</a>.</li>
</ul>

<p>The banner pictures live in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">assets/img/posts</code> in a folder with the date. Make sure your resolution is high enough (over 1500 pixels).</p>

<p>After this, the themeing is purely aesthetic.</p>

<h3 id="picking-themes">Picking Themes</h3>

<p><a href="https://www.bestjekyllthemes.com/theme/the-mvm-the-mvm.github.io/">I used this one</a>. There are excellent instructions in his README to install.</p>

<p><strong>I wanted to make HTML and CSS changes</strong>, so I went the route of downloading the project manually and copy-pasting into my project folder. To do this -</p>
<ul>
  <li>Erase everything that already exists in the folder except your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.git</code> files.</li>
  <li>Paste. Make sure to exclude their <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.git</code> files.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Tip! Some folders (like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_site/</code>) are built every time you restart the server. Make sure to make changes in the top-level <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">assets/</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_layout</code>, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_include</code> folders if you’re getting wild with code changes.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="deployment-and-beyond">Deployment and Beyond</h2>

<p>Making changes to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_config.yml</code> is the last step to build your Jekyll project. For the theme above, I had to -</p>
<ul>
  <li>Change the site settings at the top of the file</li>
  <li>Adjust the author settings</li>
  <li>Adjust the social media settings. These get tagged in every author element (an example is the author page and post pages toward the bottom)</li>
</ul>

<p>If you need help, we can set up a one-on-one consult session, or you can check the newsletter for upcoming group classes.</p>

<p>Enjoy!</p>]]></content><author><name>Vera Briene</name></author><category term="websites" /><category term="github" /><category term="DIY" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Custom author websites can rock branding... but how to you set one up for free?]]></summary></entry></feed>